During the Sunday live service, at the Synagogue Church of All Nations,
Prophet T.B. Joshua led by the Spirit of God, moves in the midst of the people
prophesying to them, revealing the root cause of their problems.
Let's listen as he speaks to this woman.
How are you?
Fine, sir.
There is a controversy over a child.
Yes, sir.
STANDARD FOR LIFE
After Prophet T.B. Joshua prophesied to the woman that there was a controversy over a child,
the man of God invited her husband to come to The SCOAN the following Sunday.
Let's watch as God Almighty opens the case file of this family.
Emmanuel! (God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
My name is Rosemary Isibor Busari. I am from Edo State.
Last week Sunday, during the first service, the man of God came to me and prophesied to me.
He said there was a controversy over a child and the prophecy is true.
My children are there: the first one, the second one, I lost the third one.
The first one is the one the man of God was talking about.
I discovered that the father would beat him all the time.
Even when the child made very little mistakes -
where one should just say: "Don't do that again"
and let the child correct himself.
But he would beat him, as if he was a goat and he wanted to kill him.
I didn't like what was happening so I told my husband
that the way this was going was not really good
and that he should rather just correct the child and that would settle it.
He got angry with me and said that he was not the father of the child.
He told me that because I said the way he was beating the child was not right,
that I should take the child to the father.
They even called a family meeting, asking me who the father was.
I said that he was the father, that there was no other man to call father.
He is the father.
I am married to him. He is the father.
I said that I didn't come to his house with any child.
There was another instance, when the child went to
take his Common Entrance Examination.
The time the child told him to collect him was different
from the time they finished. So the child was the only one left and
the school decided to take him back to their own school,
as the exam took place in another school.
When the father got to the other school and couldn't find him,
he went to his own school and found him there.
He then brought him out of the class and took him far away,
where no one would see him and started beating him.
It was so severe that it was only through the intervention of some parents
that came to pick up their own children
and the security officer of the school that the child was rescued.
He was insisting that they should leave him, that he wanted to kill the child
or let the child kill him.
He has sent me out of the house because I told him that the drugs
he bought for the fourth child - he was reacting negatively to them
and that he should stop taking the drugs.
That was why he sent me out of the house.
The third child that died - he also bought the drugs I gave to the child.
The next morning, the child died.
So, the question now!
He said he is not the father of the child?
Yes, sir.
I am Yahaya Busari.
This is my first time of coming to church. I am a Muslim.
This is my ex-wife.
I first of all want to thank you for the honour you have given to me and to our Lord Jesus Christ.
So before you talk - thank you very much.
Thank you. Because every man has discretion.
As a Muslim, Alhaji, with your position,
you heard that T.B. Joshua said this and you did not mind.
This is the first time you enter into a church in your life.
You said: "That T.B. Joshua - I will enter his church today."
I want to say thank you very much for the honour.
He who honours a prophet will receive a prophet's reward.
Amen.
Before you talk, I want to appreciate this. Thank you very much.
The bottom line of this matter is that these are my children
but whenever I want to correct my children, my wife will slap me.
They all see me as a stranger in my house.
If I enter my house, I will feel like a stranger. They no longer love me.
She turned the attention of our children only to herself.
About one month ago, I went out in the evening.
She called me that my son was ill.
I panicked and came home immediately.
I took both of them, Ramani and Maliki, straight to the pharmacy.
They gave them drugs. I didn't know that one of the drugs was garlic.
When you chew garlic, it will be smelling and having an offensive odour.
I gave the drugs to the children.
My wife then called me in the presence of the children
and asked me why I gave them these drugs -
whether I wanted to kill them.
She said I was a ritualist who wanted to kill her children.
She slaps me all the time in the presence of my children.
In short, I told her that since I am now a stranger in my house and a ritualist,
she should go and look for the father of the children.
That was why I told her that I am no longer their father.
This is a lesson to all of us. If I am standing here condemning flesh and blood,
condemning my neighbour, fighting people by name,
if I would say: "Alhaji - these people are not good, this pastor is not good", Alaji would not come here today.
This is an opportunity for me to tell him about my God and he will tell me about his own God.
SCOAN Sunday Service
Alaji, are these children living with you? How about that baby?
I have been taking care of them by myself since that time.
This baby?
Yes. I bathe him. I don't go anywhere.
Please, Man of God, you can ask them.
For the past three weeks, I bathe them.
I bathe this small boy two times a day - in the morning and evening.
I feed them and cook for them by myself since she left my house.
They are my children - all of them.
SCOAN Sunday Service
She says you are beating this child to the extent of saying he is no longer your child!
If this man really means that this child is not his own, why should he take them?
Why should he not allow you to take the one that is not his own?
But he took all of them and is living with all of them.
There are two issues now. The issue could be because of faith - that is, she is a Christian; he is a Muslim.
Maybe at the beginning... I am telling you vision, what is happening in the house.
They do not want to mention that but I am telling you some secret things that happened.
When they first married, the man is a Muslim, and she married him.
They were together and had many children.
But later she now began to say that she did not want to be a Muslim but a Christian.
That would begin to cause what? If the husband says "no"!!
Exactly. She always says so.
Clap for Jesus Christ! Rise up!
Rise up! Rise up!
They would not mention that.
There are many issues between husband and wife that they would not mention.
But as a pastor, I know.
Your first time entering the church as Alaji and you have never done so.
And you honour that invitation because of these children.
And you people are here and not even telling us the real reason, why you are fighting.
But not until I said that this is the cause.
And you are now saying: "Yes, this is the cause."
Man of God, when they called me and said that I should come,
I said I must go straight away, since it was T.B. Joshua that invited me.
Because I watch your programme every day in my house. You can ask her.
Both day and night.
You can ask her.
You can ask her, Man of God.
You can ask any of my children.
He watches Emmanuel TV every day - even in the night.
When I would be sleeping and have to go to the bathroom, I would see him.
He would be glued to the television every night, watching Emmanuel TV.
My father watches Emmanuel TV every day.
That's how we were able to come here and solve this problem.
It is true.
I said: "As far as it is T.B. Joshua, I will be there immediately". I moved.
Thank you.
SCOAN Sunday Service
Please, Man of God, my wife said that I killed her father and my own son.
She said that I am a ritualist.
That is one of the reasons, why I am here so that you can touch me
and let me confess, how I killed her father and my own son.
Ok.
No, wait.
Next week, we will continue this.
But I want to assure you that the wisdom of Solomon is still there.
SCOAN Sunday Service
Thank you very much.
STANDARD FOR LIFE
The following Sunday, God continued to use Prophet T.B. Joshua to demonstrate the wisdom of Solomon
in the life of this couple.
What is God's opinion concerning this family?
Will reconciliation be possible?
Let's watch what happened next.
Let's take a look at the book of Romans 13.
SCOAN Sunday Service
Let me take a reading from the verse 1.
"Let every soul be subject to the governing authorities.
For there is no authority except from God,
and the authorities that exist are appointed by God."
Verse 2.
"Therefore whoever resists the authority resists the ordinance of God,
and those who resist will bring judgement on themselves."
Verse 3.
"For rulers are not a terror to good works, but to evil..."
Let's read it together and take note of that. Write it on your paper.
That is the area we want to talk about.
Romans 13:3. "For rulers are not a terror to good works, but to evil..."
Hallelujah!
Amen.
Let's take our topic this way.
MESSAGE TITLE: Good Christians are Good Citizens
Tell your neighbour.
Good Christians are good citizens.
Going by Romans 13, the concepts of Christianity and good citizenship are inseparable.
They are both synonymous; both go in tandem, pari passu.
Tell your neighbour.
Whatever makes men good Christians makes them good citizens.
Tell your neighbour once again.
Yes.
When you look at the constitution of your country -
"thou shalt not kill, though shalt not destroy,
though shalt not this, though shalt not that."
Whatever makes you a good Christian, makes you a good citizen.
I am a good citizen.
Tell your neighbour.
If you are a good citizen, you must pray against broken homes.
Because at the beginning of marriage - for better, for worse.
In every law, once you get married - the law says: "For better, for worse; come rain, come shine."
Tell your neighbour: "I am a good citizen."
So if you are a good citizen, you must pray against broken homes.
I know, what it is to come from a broken home.
When I was one year old, I was left with my mum.
I know the pain and agony.
It is not the wish and it can never be the wish of our Lord and Saviour, Jesus Christ,
to see these children without motherly care at this young age.
Coming to the issue of faith.
I am a Christian; I am not a religious man.
Striving against people and standing on the pulpit and speaking against others -
we are fighting the wrong battle.
We are to battle the spiritual entities that cause tension,
killing, stealing and destruction.
We are not fighting the physical appearance that we are seeing.
Our battle is not against flesh and blood.
The Gospel of our Lord, Jesus Christ, is the Good News.
The message is righteousness. When you hear it, it gladens your heart.
We have the ability to preach. Jesus makes it happen in the person of the Holy Ghost.
As a Christian, you need to apply yourself to your work;
you need to apply yourself to your duty, as a Christian soldier.
Tell your neighbour.
Apply yourself to your work, to your duty, as a Christian soldier.
When soldiers in the physical world go to work, they carry guns, ammunition.
But we don't carry such things.
Our weapons are not this ammunition we see, the guns we see but spiritual.
It is not the physical appearance that is our enemy.
We are not fighting the physical appearance we are seeing.
If you are not armed for battle, you will fight the wrong battle.
Can you tell your neighbour.
Because if you are armed,
the Saviour that armed you will tell you the battle to fight.
SCOAN Sunday Service
Come, sir.
It is like I am telling this gentleman: "Oh, you are going to war. Have this weapon."
But if I will give you a weapon, I will tell you how to use it.
I won't just give you a weapon without teaching you or telling you, how to use it.
So the people that are fighting, striving against people,
standing on the pulpit,
speaking against others:
"That man is not good, that religion is not good, that person is not good" -
they are not armed.
If you are armed- the person that armed you, will tell you, how to use this weapon.
Tell your neighbour.
If you are not armed for battle, you will fight the wrong battle.
SCOAN Sunday Service
If we are not armed for battle, we will fight the wrong battle.
If we are not armed for battle, we will not be able to listen
to the inner voice of the Holy Spirit.
SCOAN Sunday Service
Like country to country, when they are going to war,
before they give you a weapon, they have to take you to some kind of training -
how to use a weapon, the time to use it.
The battalion leader will tell you.
They will appoint you to the battalion. This is the leader that will lead you into war.
And he will teach you, tell you time and when to shoot.
Without hearing the signal, you cannot shoot.
When you hear a certain signal, it is telling you that they are close.
They have a sign.
Each country has its sign.
That is why when the United Kingdom gives sign to its soldiers in battle,
Nigeria will not understand what they are saying.
If Nigeria gives sign to its soldiers,
the British government will also not understand what they are trying to say.
Because they give you arms, they must also tell you what to use, how to use it, and the time to use it.
Tell your neighbour.
If you are not armed for battle, you will fight the wrong battle.
If you are not armed for battle, you will not be able to listen
to the inner voice of the Holy Ghost.
The concepts of Christianity and good citizenship are inseparable.
They both are synonymous.
Tell your neighbour.
Good Christians are good citizens.
I can't hear you.
So, my brothers,
you have heard me.
SCOAN Sunday Service
I am to preach, teach, but Jesus makes it work;
Jesus makes it happen in the person of the Holy Ghost.
Thank you.
SCOAN Sunday Service
You have seen the family.
They will continue to live together.
The Lord is there to determine their faith.
If this man could be here with me for one week,
I would only tell him about my Lord Jesus Christ
but I have no power to force anyone to be a Christian.
I have no power of my own
Holy Spirit, I look upon You, help me
I want to change you at all cost;
you want to change me to your place too at all cost -
this is where crisis comes.
Faith is a thing of the Spirit.
Thank you. You may be seated.
SCOAN Sunday Service
Go and take care of your home.
Take care of these children.
For the past seven days now,
what marriage is all about -
he has learnt and seen it.
But one thing I have discovered in your family
that there is a spirit of mental disorder in your family.
There is a mental disorder in your family; if you go back to your home and check,
someone in your family is mental.
Yes, Man of God.
Who?
His name is Christian; he's my younger brother.
He's mental.
Yes, Man of God.
That thing is in the family; it started from your grandfather.
And you too have depression.
Yes, Man of God.
And when this depression comes, you can abandon home and walk out.
SCOAN Sunday Service
So this is what we have to work on.
We should not hide under faith
and begin to cause crisis.
Don't use faith to cover up.
"Jesus is Lord; Jesus is Deliverer" -
deliver them! "Jesus is Lord" - show them the Lord.
We should not use that to cover up and begin to preach.
But what of that spirit that kills, steals and destroys?
Look at what the Bible says in that verse 3.
It says in Romans 13:3: "For rulers are not a terror to good works, but to evil..."
Love is very strong and we are known by our love.
For someone to be in the presence of God -
what else again?
SCOAN Sunday Service
Prophet T.B. Joshua is used by God Almighty, as a commissioned solution provider,
as speaking with divine wisdom and direction,
the Busari family is restored.
They affectionately embrace and kiss each other,
proving that their past is over and a happy future lies before them.
Thank you, Jesus Christ.
SCOAN Sunday Service
TESTIMONY TIME
I am Alhaji Busari from Kwara State.
You are welcome, sir. And who are the people standing beside you here?
They are my wife and children.
I thank God. I have seen big changes.
Before, my wife and I used to quarrel but immediately we came here,
she changed and is now behaving well.
We are now alright and no longer quarrel.
So there is peace restored in the marriage?
Yes, we've been living in peace since we came here.
Before you came here, is it true that both of you have been separated for some weeks?
Yes, we separated; I asked her to go but now we have settled.
And how do you now see your family, the peace that is in your family,
and the way you are treating your wife and your children?
I thank God that there is now peace. Peace has been restored in my family.
2. Corinthians 5:18 states: "Now all things are of God who has reconciled us to Himself through Jesus Christ
and has given us the ministry of reconciliation."
Not only was the Busari family restored and reconciled through God's wisdom
but they were also given a cash gift of 300,000 naira by Prophet T.B. Joshua and Emmanuel TV Partners.
He gave us 300,000 naira.
I thank him very much for giving us this money.
He is a true man of God.
So you were not expecting anything like this?
I was very surprised to see the amount of money he gave me and my family.
It is a lot of money for us.
So what can you say concerning how God is using Prophet T.B. Joshua?
God is using him to help many people.
If not for the man of God, my wife and I would have been divorced by now.
We really thank God Almighty for your life. And what are you going to use this money for now?
I will use it for my business and to take care of my family.
Wonderful. We thank God.
Finally, after all that God has done for you, what do you want to tell viewers
about what Jesus is doing, what God Almighty is doing here in The SCOAN?
Although I have been watching Emmanuel TV and I know what he can do,
I thank God that if anybody has a problem like me,
they can run to him and he will solve it.
My name is Mrs Rosemary Busari. I am from Edo State.
The man next to me is my husband, and these are my children.
God has done a very wonderful thing in my life and family.
Before I came here, there were problems in my family and marriage -
terrible problems. We could not stay together without quarrelling.
He finally sent me out and this was not the first time he had sent me out.
When I came to The SCOAN, to my surprise,
the man of God singled me out from the multitude of people that were around.
He prayed for me, called my family and reunited us.
Now, we are living together happily.
I am grateful to God and the man of God.
Today, he gave us 300,000 naira.
For us to use and be happy. I thank God.
So since you came to this church, God has now reconciled you with your husband
and restored peace to the family.
Just tell us the changes you have been seeing in your marriage and family now.
We are together now but before now, we didn't stay together.
Jesus Christ loves us and is concerned about us.
He wants to be involved in everything about us
and walk us through whatever life brings.
If God is involved in our matter, it does not matter who else is involved.
My name is Wasiu Busari.
This is my father, my mum and my brothers.
I thank God for the reconciliation of my father, mother and brothers.
For three weeks, my father and mother were separated.
It was only my father, who took care of us; I didn't know where my mum went.
But I am happy now that Prophet T.B. Joshua has brought us back together
and we are now inseparable.
So you are very happy now that peace is back in this family?
Yes.
We thank God. Do you believe now with your parents back together
that you have a very bright future and as you go to school, you'll become someone great in the future?
Yes, I believe.
My name is Baniki Busari.
Who are the people beside you?
This is my dad, my mum and my brothers.
Just tell us, what God has done for this family since you came to The SCOAN.
I thank God for what Prophet T.B. Joshua has done in the life of my parents.
Before, there were always fights, quarrels and arguments.
But now, I thank God for what He has done in our lives.
Now there is peace?
Yes, it is true, I believe.
Wonderful. We thank God Almighty for the peace that has been restored to this family.
My name is Ramoni Busari.
Who are the people beside you?
This is my father, my mum and my brothers.
Just tell us, what God has done for your family.
Before, my mother and father were separated but they are together now.
And you are very happy for that?
Yes.
We thank God Almighty. This is a wonderful thing that God has done in this family.
Waving their hands joyfully, they give thanks to God.
The restoration and reconciliation of the Busari family is proof
that there is never a problem that Jesus Christ cannot solve.
We believe you have been inspired by the clip you have just watched.
Click here to subscribe to witness more of God's power at work in our generation today
and stay up-to-date with the latest prophecies, deliverances, sermons and testimonies
from the Synagogue Church of All Nations.
Emmanuel TV - Changing lives, Changing nations, and Changing the world.
TT: Lizz Ndungu
RV: Pavel Tatyana Zheleznyakov 17/06/2018